<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-10-01T23:00:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shawn Manuel</title><subtitle>Shawn Manuel&apos;s personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">AIxMH - OpenProjection: An Introduction to Machine Learning in Python for Mental Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/09/26/openprojection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AIxMH - OpenProjection: An Introduction to Machine Learning in Python for Mental Health" /><published>2023-09-26T02:59:46-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-26T02:59:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/09/26/openprojection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/09/26/openprojection.html"><![CDATA[<p>It is said that we do not perceive the world as it is, but as we are. Such poetic truisms capture a key phenomenon that the fields of philosophy, psychology and neurosicence have been grappling with for millenia, centuries and decades, respectively: individuals experience themselves and the world in their own unique and rather impenetrable way. Getting to the core subjective experience holds great promise for many other herculean tasks, such as understanding, preventing and treating the distorsions of subjective experience that lead to mental health diagnoses and ultimately, revealing the nature of consciousness itself. Obviously, we won’t be solving the Hard Problem anytime soon, but we can attempt a first pass at quantifying verbal reports of subjective experience and relating them to mental health (broadly construed).</p>

<p>Among the classics in psychology are <strong>projective measures</strong>, such as the Thematic Apperception Test (TAT), which are founded on the idea that people reveal aspects of themselves when confronted with non-obvious situations. In keeping with the popular adage at the beginning of this section, the TAT is designed to assess variations in how individuals interpret ambiguous situations. However, subjecting its results to automated, reproducible, quantitative statistical verification has proven difficult….until now.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/shwnmnl/OpenProjection">OpenProjection</a> is a basic open-source machine learning project I designed during my master’s. Its main use is as a very beginner-friendly, step-by-step tutorial for machine learning in Python. It covers different types of supervised learning problems, including both regression and classification, as well as an embedded unsupervised learning problem.</p>

<p>The entire thing can be run from start to finish in <a href="https://colab.research.google.com/github/shwnmnl/OpenProjection/blob/main/OpenProjection.ipynb">Google Colab</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is said that we do not perceive the world as it is, but as we are. Such poetic truisms capture a key phenomenon that the fields of philosophy, psychology and neurosicence have been grappling with for millenia, centuries and decades, respectively: individuals experience themselves and the world in their own unique and rather impenetrable way. Getting to the core subjective experience holds great promise for many other herculean tasks, such as understanding, preventing and treating the distorsions of subjective experience that lead to mental health diagnoses and ultimately, revealing the nature of consciousness itself. Obviously, we won’t be solving the Hard Problem anytime soon, but we can attempt a first pass at quantifying verbal reports of subjective experience and relating them to mental health (broadly construed).]]></summary></entry></feed>